Peter Roper

Inzai Makinohara, Chiba

linkedin.com/in/peter-roper

+81 070 4127 4930

https://hotbertaa.github.io

■ peter.roper.jp@gmail.com

**** +81 0476 374455

I am a versatile UI/UX designer and front end developer with 15+ years of experience. My skill set is broad; ranging from UI design and protyping to front end development & graphic design. I enjoy each aspect and the variety that this brings. I like to take the lead in projects and push things forward while striving to inspire those working with me. I have an optimistic and enthusiastic attitude, with a focus on producing captivating design and simplicity in delivery.

Experience

UI/UX Designer & Web Developer @ Geronigo

🗖 2017-present 👂 Chiba, Japan

Geronigo 'Every Adventure' are an international booking agency with over 5000 activity venues spread across the world. Created by the founding members of Go Ballistic.

Whilst continuing to manage Go Ballistics portfolio of websites, my main responsibilities transitioned more to design conceptualisation, branding and the UI/UX aspects of forming the new Geronigo brand and websites.

- Created the user flow, UI & branding of Geronigo's main website from prototyping through to the front end build.
- Established the new UI of the RezBot marketing website and built the front end.
- Created animated prototype's for the UI of RezBot's event planner & availability booker mobile apps.
- Undertook user research of post booking guests, with the goal of improving the user experience of websites & applications.
- Created split testing on design iterations & website features and measured impact via google analytics.
- Created the geronigo design system and was responsible for maintaining the consistent use of the companies style guidelines between divisions within the company.

UI Designer & Web Developer @ Go Ballistic

🗖 2013-2017 👂 Chiba, Japan

Upon moving to Japan I continued to work for Go Ballistic, the parent company of The Activity People.

Languages

English - Native

⊕ Japanese - IntermediateComprehension & Readingtargeting JPLT N4 & N3 proficiency in 2020

Personal

British Nationality

Japanese Permenant Resident

Skills



My role evolved over the time I worked for the company, but ultimately my responsibilities remained consistent in the core use of design, development & production.

- Transitioned all websites to responsive css with a shared css template structure, using a core SASS codebase.
- Modernised the UI design and created a new underlying javascript framework for the companies portfolio of websites.
- Developed the UI for a new voucher booking process and optimised for mobile viewing.
- Updated the design & branding of established websites, whilst also adding new brands as further activities joined the activity network.
- Designed & built the front end of the original RezBot cms booking system.
- Conducted inhouse user research on website features and competitor analysis - with the goal of improving website user experience.

Web Developer @ Go Ballistic

🗖 2011-2013 👂 Chiba, Japan

Graphic Web Designer @ Go Ballistic

1 2009-2011 **♀** Chiba, Japan

Graphic Web Designer @ The Activity People

The Activity People provide an extensive range of experience days, gift experiences, driving experiences and team building activities.

My responsibilities included web design and development, graphic and print design. I was responsible for the creation of an extensive portfolio of activity based websites.

- I was lead developer for SEO optimisation of thebigshoot.co.uk, one of the companies leading search engine ranking websites.
- Part of a development team which created the companies booking system.
- Developed multi activity search functionality and google map integration.
- Created an extensive portfolio of brand logo's and brand design.

Education

B.Sc Product Design & Development

- **1999-2002**
- University of Salford

Passions



Philosophy

"Complexity is your enemy. Any fool can make something complicated. It is hard to make something simple"

- Richard Branson

"When you're chewing on life's gristle, Don't grumble, give a whistle! And this'll help things turn out for the best"

- Eric Idle

References

Contact details & references supplied upon request.

Bernie Janes

CEO @ Geronigo

linkedin.com/in/bernie-janes-7852996

Daniel Janes

Chief Technology Officer @ Geronigo

linkedin.com/in/danielpjanes

Graphic Web Designer @ Valehall

□ 2005-2006 **♀** Sheffield, UK

Working for a print production company; my role comprised both graphic design for print and web design and development of the companies websites.

English Instructor @ Nova Corporation

🗖 2003-2005 👂 Kashiwa, Chiba

Recent Projects

Geronigo

UI designer and front end developer for Geronigo, an international adventure bookings service. Recent work has been on SEO optimisation and site performance, working closely with google insights.

RezBot Marketing

Ul designer, front end developer & content creator for RezBot, a suite of products to aid activity suppliers. Built with bootstrap with influences from the google material guidelines.

RezBot Bookings

UI designer, prototyping work for a proposed mobile app for RezBots booking manager, produced using Sketch & Principle.

Geronigo Event Planner

UI designer, prototyping work for a proposed 3rd iteration of the Geronigo event planner, produced using Sketch & Principle.

Adventure Cards

Lead designer, front end developer for Adventure Cards website.

Escape This

Lead designer, front end developer & content creator for Escape This, a newly established escape room opened in Perth.

Please visit my portfolio found at **https://hotbertaa.github.io** for a more indepth overview of my latest work and to find urls to the websites I have created.